moneyadviceservice.org.uk 2012-06-25

# Privacy policy : Money Advice Service

This privacy policy applies to 'the Money Advice Service'. This includes our telephone Money Advice Line, face-to-face appointment service and the Money Advice Service website. 

**We took over responsibility for the Moneymadeclear service from the Financial Services Authority (FSA) on 26 April 2010. If you provided the FSA with personal information before this date please see ‘Transfer of the Moneymadeclear service’ below to find out how this affects you.**

This policy together with our website terms and conditions sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide us with, will be processed by us or our delivery partners.

Any information you provide will be treated in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. We won’t try to sell you anything and you won’t receive unsolicited telephone calls or mail from us or any third parties as a result of personal data being provided to us. Your information will only be used for quality, training and evaluation purposes, to help us monitor and improve the Money Advice Service, or to provide services you have requested (such as an order for printed publications, or a telephone or face-to-face appointment). By using the Money Advice Service website and submitting your information to us, you agree to us using your personal information in accordance with this policy.

Please notify us by email to [enquiries@moneyadviceservice.org.uk](mailto:enquiries@moneyadviceservice.org.uk) if you have provided us with personal information and you do not wish it to be used as described below, or you wish to see which information we hold about you as a result of your contact with us. 

* * *

## What information are we collecting?

  * **If you talk to us face to face or on the phone**   
We may ask for personal information about you, such as your name, address, telephone number or date of birth.
  * **If you use the Money Advice Service website**   
We log your IP (Internet Protocol) address and session information (such as the duration of the visit and the type of browser used).  Subject to legal requirements from time to time, we may also use cookies.    
Cookies are small text files that are often created when you visit a website, and which are stored in the cookie directory of your computer.  A cookie may be created when you visit us. Cookies are used to improve services for you through, for example: 
    * Enabling a service to recognise your device so you don’t have to give the same information several times during one task.
    * Recognising that you may already have given a username and password so you don’t need to do it for every web page requested.
    * Measuring how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and more relevant to you.
  
We may use both permanent and session cookies.  The permanent cookie stores a random number on your computer or other device to help us count the number of times users return to our website.  The session cookie lets us know which pages within our site you visit.  Permanent cookies do not expire when you leave our website and may be used on subsequent visits to the website.  Session cookies expire when you close your internet browser. 

The cookie (whether permanent or session) does not contain any personal information about you, and it cannot be used to identify an individual user. 

To see a full list of the cookies we may use when you visit one of our websites see Cookies we use. 

You can manage cookies yourself and learn about them by visiting [Internet browser cookies – what they are and how to manage them](http://www.direct.gov.uk/managingcookies).

We sometimes collect personal information through optional online surveys from some areas of our website. These are usually delivered by other companies, so a different privacy policy will apply.  We rely on these third parties to obtain your consent for us to use this information. Additional information about the survey will be available to see before you decide whether or not to take part. 

You may also provide us with your address or contact details to receive further information or guidance, receive printed material (such as Money Advice Service printed guides) or to ask that we call you back by telephone. This is collected using online forms. 

* * *

## What will we do with this information?

  * **If you talk to us face to face or on the phone**  
We will use your personal information to provide you with any information or advice that you ask for, to reply to any correspondence and to manage the service that we provide. We will also use it to analyse information such as where in the country users come from, what type of questions they are asking, and whether we were able to give them information or advice that was useful. We also want to hear users’ views on the Money Advice Service and any improvements they might suggest. If this is something you agree to help us with, then we would need to pass on your contact details to the independent research agency commissioned by us so that they can get in touch with you. Neither we nor our appointed agency will try to sell you anything.
  * **If you use the Money Advice Service website**   
Subject to legal requirements in place from time to time, your IP address and session information are only used for system administration and to provide statistics, which we use to evaluate use of the site. We may also use cookies to provide anonymous information using various services. To find out more about these services and what each of these cookies if used for, see Cookies we use. 

If you provide us with your contact or address details using one of our online forms we will only use this information to deliver the services you have requested.

If we would like to use your personal information for any other purpose than those stated above, we will contact you to ask for your consent before doing so.

* * *

## Who will see this information?

  * **If you talk to us face to face or on the phone**   
All personal information will be fully protected in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and will be kept strictly confidential. The only people with access to it will be those involved in providing, evaluating or managing the Money Advice Service. This policy does not cover any other service that we may refer you to in order to complete your enquiry.
  * **If you use the Money Advice Service website**   
For information about the services we use to collect anonymous site usage information please see the links to relevant services within Cookies we use. 

If you asked us to call you back or requested printed material (such as a Money Advice Service guide or the Parent’s guide to money), we use third parties to provide these services, so your information will be passed on to them for this purpose only. They will not pass your information on to anyone else or use it for any other purpose.

We may pass on your personal information if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal information in order to comply with any legal obligation or in order to enforce or apply our website terms and conditions or for the purposes of the prevention or detection of a crime.

* * *

## How do we protect your personal information?

The Money Advice Service makes every effort (through physical, organisational and technological measures) to ensure that your personal information is held securely and to safeguard against unauthorised access to your personal information.  Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. We strive to protect your personal information after we’ve received it, however you acknowledge that the privacy of your communications and personal information can never be completely guaranteed when it is being transmitted.

* * *

## Changes to this policy

Please note that this  policy may change from time to time and the new privacy policy will be published on the Money Advice Service  website.  Regularly reviewing this page ensures you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we will share it with other parties.

* * *

## Transfer of the Moneymadeclear service 

**The Money Advice Service was launched on 4 April 2011.   Before this date, the service operated as Moneymadeclear from the Consumer Financial Education Body (CFEB).**

The Financial Services Act 2010 ('the Act') received Royal Assent on 8 April 2010. The Act made amendments to the Financial Services and Markets Act 2000. These amendments required the FSA to establish the Consumer Financial Education Body (CFEB) and they also transferred responsibility for the Moneymadeclear service to CFEB on 26 April 2010.

To enable CFEB to continue providing the Moneymadeclear service, the FSA forwarded all personal information collected through it on this date to CFEB. With the launch of the Money Advice Service on 4 April 2011, this data was transferred to us on that date.  As explained above in this privacy policy, we won’t try to sell you anything and you won’t receive unsolicited telephone calls or mail from the  FSA or any third parties. We will only use your information as outlined in this policy.

If you previously shared personal information with the FSA (which may include your home address, email address and telephone number) while using the Moneymadeclear service, and you do not wish us to hold it, let us know by email to [enquiries@moneyadviceservice.org.uk](mailto:enquiries@moneyadviceservice.org.uk). 

* * *

## Cookies we use

This page lists the cookies that may be used from one of our websites and what they are used for. This information forms part of our Privacy policy.

  * **AddThis** (Addthis.com/cf.addthis.com/l.addthiscdn.com/s7.addthis.com)  
AddThis is a service that allows you to quickly share pages you like on our websites using Twitter and Facebook. Some of these cookies are automatically removed when you close your browser. The cookie stored allows us to understand what visitors want to share and not to share, so we can improve the service you receive. To find out more visit [www.addthis.com/privacy](http://www.addthis.com/privacy).
  * **Core Motives** (databroker-us.coremotives.com)  
Core Motives is a service used by our customer relationship management system. This temporary cookie allows us to understand what visitors want to use and not to use, so we can improve the service you receive. The cookie is automatically removed when you close your browser. To find out more visit [http://coremotives.com/privacy-statement](http://coremotives.com/privacy-statement/).
  * **QuantcastUK** (quantcast.com)  
As well as offering 3rd party measurement to Publishers & Marketers; Quantcast offer a proprietary technology called ‘Lookalike Modelling.’ Quantcast Lookalikes are models of customers, built using user data. This allows us to profile the affinities of site behaviours by finding out what is unique about our particular audience.
  * **Doubleclick** (Doubleclick.net/fls.doubleclick.net/ad.uk.doubleclick.net)  
The Doubleclick service is a Google product used by our marketing teams to monitor the effectiveness of our advertising. Some of these cookies are automatically removed when you close your browser. The cookie stored allows us to understand what visitors want to use and not to use, so we can improve the service you receive. To find out more visit [www.google.com/privacy/ads](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/).
  * **Google Analytics** (www.google-analytics.com/ssl.google-analytics.com)  
We use Google Analytics to record how our websites are used. Some of these cookies are automatically removed when you close your browser. The cookie stored allows us to understand what visitors want to use and not to use, so we can improve the service you receive. To find out more visit [www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html](http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html). 
  * **Money Advice Service health check** (healthcheck.moneyadviceservice.org.uk)  
When you use our health check we store a number of cookies which are required for it to work:
    * CookieTest and js_enabled – used to tell the health check whether you have cookies and Javascript enabled in your browser. These cookies are automatically removed when you close your browser.
    * .EpiServerLogin, UserIsLoggedIn, .ASPXROLES and LoginAttemptsCount – used to tell the health check whether you are logged in and information about your permissions. These cookies are automatically removed when you close your browser or after 20 minutes of inactivity.
    * HasClickedExternalLink – used to tell the health check if you have clicked on an external link. This is so we can warn you if you are leaving our website. This cookie is automatically removed when you close your browser.
    * QuestionnaireHistory – used to temporarily remember the answers to your questions while you are using the health check and allows us to give you your action plan. This cookie is automatically removed when you close your browser, so no-one else can see the answers you gave.
    * ActionPlanState – stores information to remember which parts of your action plan are currently expanded so if you register and come back to the health check later on it will be as you left it. This cookie is automatically removed after 30 days if you do not log back in within that time.
    * Cm_vid, cm_medium, cm_sid, cd_campid and cm_mid – cookies starting with one of these are used to help us track the effectiveness of our campaign advertising. They allow us to understand what visitors want to use and not to use, so we can improve the service you receive, but are automatically removed when you close your browser.
  * **Money Advice Service websites** (moneyadviceservice.org.uk / divorce.moneyadviceservice.org.uk / tables.moneyadviceservice.org.uk)  
Cookies from the Money Advice Service websites are used for Google Analytics (__utma, __utmb, __utmc and __utmz)
  * **Mookie** (Mookie1.com/b3-UK.mookie1.com/t.mookie1.com)  
This is an advertising customisation service. This cookie is used with Doubleclick (above) if you have responded from another site to a Money Advice Service advert or advertising link, to ensure we advertise in the right places to the right people. Some of these cookies are automatically removed when you close your browser. To find out more visit [www.mookie1.com/privacy.php](http://www.mookie1.com/privacy.php). 
  * **Typekit** (use.typekit.com)  
We use this service to display a font to you that is part of our website design. This cookie is temporary and is removed automatically when you close your browser. To find out more visit <http://typekit.com/policies/privacy>.

## Survey privacy policy

### Who is carrying out this survey? 

We, the Money Advice Service, have commissioned the market research agency eDigitalResearch PLC of Vanbrugh House, Hedge End, Hampshire, SO30 2AF, company number: 5424597 to carry out this survey on our behalf. 

Your privacy is important to us and we will take care to safeguard it. We understand that you may have concerns about the privacy and security of your personal information and we would therefore like to take this opportunity to explain our privacy policy. Please note, this policy only covers information collected through this survey. y. You can read the main Money Advice Service privacy policy at [www.moneyadviceservice.org.uk/privacypolicy.aspx](http://www.moneyadviceservice.org.uk/privacypolicy.aspx). 

### When and what information do we collect?

We only collect personal data such as your name, telephone number, age, post code and email address when you volunteer your personal information by completing this survey. We and eDigitalResearch PLC have security measures in place to prevent the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information that this survey collects. We understand that some of you may not wish to provide some of the information requested. You may still participate in our research programme and continue to visit the Money Advice Service website even if you do not wish to provide any or all of the personal information requested in the survey. 

### What do we do with your personal information?

By providing personal data to eDigitalResearch PLC you consent to their sharing it with us. Your information will be used for research purposes only and may be stored for up to two years. 

If you provided your name,telephone number and email address to participate in our market research, you consent to us or another market research agency appointed by us contacting you again for a follow-up research interview or interviews. Neither we nor our appointed agency will try to sell you anything. 

We will store and handle your information in accordance with the Data Protection Act. Please visit <http://www.ico.gov.uk/Home/for_organisations/data_protection_guide.aspx> for more information about this. 

### Contacting us

Please notify us by email to [enquiries@moneyadviceservice.org.uk](mailto:enquiries@moneyadviceservice.org.uk) if you provided us with personal information and you:

  * **do not** wish your personal information to be used as described above; or
  * wish to see the personal information we hold about you as a result of you completing this survey.
